<resources>
    <string name="app_name">fNIR Application</string>
    <string name="Open">Open</string>
    <string name="Close">Close</string>

    <string name="ble_not_supported">BLE is not supported</string>
    <string name="label_data">Data:</string>
    <string name="label_device_address">Device address:</string>
    <string name="label_state">State:</string>
    <string name="no_data">No data</string>
    <string name="connected">Connected</string>
    <string name="disconnected">Disconnected</string>
    <string name="title_devices">BLE Device Scan</string>
    <string name="error_bluetooth_not_supported">Bluetooth not supported.</string>

    <string name="unknown_device">Unknown device</string>
    <string name="unknown_characteristic">Unknown characteristic</string>
    <string name="unknown_service">Unknown service</string>

    <!-- Menu items -->
    <string name="menu_connect">Connect</string>
    <string name="menu_disconnect">Disconnect</string>
    <string name="menu_scan">Scan</string>
    <string name="menu_stop">Stop</string>



    <!-- TODO: Remove or change this placeholder text -->
    <string name="hello_blank_fragment">Hello blank fragment</string>
    <string name="about_the_fnir">About the fNIR</string>
    <string name="concussions">Implementing Concussions</string>
    <string name="about_description">Functional Near-Infrared Spectroscopy (fNIR) is a recently developed technology that uses infrared light to measure changes in the concentration of hemoglobin in the cortex of the brain. It provides affordable, safe, and portable brain imaging that other brain imaging technologies are not even capable of producing. The fNIR can easily be combined with other brain imaging technologies and includes portable and wireless systems, data processing algorithms, and end-user software. fNIRs have been proven to be great neuroimaging tools for researchers and doctors for they are able to measure brain activity during emotional, intellectual, and motor tasks. The fNIR has proved that it is very effective for studying perception and emotion-related changes of the brain in both adults and children.
    </string>
    <string name="concussion_description">In the NFL, any serious blow to the head and the subsequent symptoms displayed by the player requires the medical personnel to remove the player from the field immediately and perform a neurological examination. If he is diagnosed with a concussion, he cannot return to the game. But the problem is that the players return way too soon. Even though the player will not be cleared for another week, it is common for players to take painkillers and return to the next game. Our fNIR app will allow for players to be tested everyday without the hassle of going to the hospital for an MRI to see if they can return to play that day. After reading a bunch of studies, we learned that after the initial impact, there is an increased CBF, or cerebral blood flow, which decreases over the next few days, which causes dizziness and loss of cognitive abilities. Concussions very often lead anemia which is a lack of hemoglobin in someones blood. As a result, we came up with an empirical way of testing for concussion symptoms. First, the players must go through a baseline test before the season starts, then they take the test again after their injury. The empirical data is achieved by finding the area of the enclosure between the oxy and deoxy hemoglobin plot line of the baseline graph, then comparing it to that of the post injury graph. This will accurately compare the differences in oxy hemoglobin spikes and deoxy hemoglobin dips between the two sets of data. There needs to be a lot more studies done to correlate concussion symptoms and hemoglobin levels, and really concussions in general as they are not yet fully understood. But we think this will be a great start to accurately diagnose a players neurohealth.
    </string>

</resources>
