<resources>
    <string name="app_name">fNIR</string>
    <string name="Open">Open</string>
    <string name="Close">Close</string>

    <string name="ble_not_supported">BLE is not supported</string>
    <string name="label_data">Data:</string>
    <string name="label_device_address">Device address:</string>
    <string name="label_state">State:</string>
    <string name="no_data">No data</string>
    <string name="connected">Connected</string>
    <string name="disconnected">Disconnected</string>
    <string name="title_devices">BLE Device Scan</string>
    <string name="error_bluetooth_not_supported">Bluetooth not supported.</string>

    <string name="unknown_device">Unknown device</string>
    <string name="unknown_characteristic">Unknown characteristic</string>
    <string name="unknown_service">Unknown service</string>

    <!-- Menu items -->
    <string name="menu_connect">Connect</string>
    <string name="menu_disconnect">Disconnect</string>
    <string name="menu_scan">Scan</string>
    <string name="menu_stop">Stop</string>


    <!-- TODO: Remove or change this placeholder text -->
    <string name="hello_blank_fragment">Hello blank fragment</string>
    <string name="about_the_fnir">Why fNIR?</string>
    <string name="concussions">Implementing Concussions</string>
    <string name="about_description2">Functional Near-Infrared Spectroscopy (fNIR) is a way to measure brain activity using infrared light to measure the concentration of oxygenated and deoxygenated hemoglobin in the brain. The goal is similar to that of other brain imaging devices, such as fMRI andEEG, but fNIR is portable and cheaper. It provides affordable, safe, and portable brain imaging that other brain imaging technologies are not even capable of producing. The fNIR can easily be combined with other brain imaging technologies and includes portable and wireless systems, data processing algorithms, and end-user software. fNIRs have been proven to be great neuroimaging tools for researchers and doctors for they are able to measure brain activity during emotional, intellectual, and motor tasks. The fNIR has proved that it is very effective for studying perception and emotion-related changes of the brain in both adults and children.
    </string>
    <string name="concussion_description">In the NFL, any serious blow to the head and the subsequent symptoms displayed by the player requires the medical personnel to remove the player from the field immediately and perform a neurological examination. If he is diagnosed with a concussion, he cannot return to the game. But the problem is that the players return way too soon. Even though the player will not be cleared for another week, it is common for players to take painkillers and return to the next game. Our fNIR app will allow for players to be tested everyday without the hassle of going to the hospital for an MRI to see if they can return to play that day. After reading a bunch of studies, we learned that after the initial impact, there is an increased CBF, or cerebral blood flow, which decreases over the next few days, which causes dizziness and loss of cognitive abilities. Concussions very often lead anemia which is a lack of hemoglobin in someones blood. As a result, we came up with an empirical way of testing for concussion symptoms. First, the players must go through a baseline test before the season starts, then they take the test again after their injury. The empirical data is achieved by finding the area of the enclosure between the oxy and deoxy hemoglobin plot line of the baseline graph, then comparing it to that of the post injury graph. This will accurately compare the differences in oxy hemoglobin spikes and deoxy hemoglobin dips between the two sets of data. There needs to be a lot more studies done to correlate concussion symptoms and hemoglobin levels, and really concussions in general as they are not yet fully understood. But we think this will be a great start to accurately diagnose a players neurohealth.
    </string>

    <string name="about_description">
        "       Functional Near Infrared Spectroscopy, or fNIR for short, is a device that generates real-time brain analysis by directing near infrared light into specific regions of the brain and measuring the quantity of light reflected back to the device. The amount reflected depends on many factors, but the goal of fNIR is to use a wavelength of light so that oxygen is the main source of absorption (if there is a high concentration of oxygen, then very little light will be reflected). That is why two LEDs are used in this device, one emitting light at a wavelength of 730 nanometers and another of 850 nanometers.
        By collecting the intensity of the light reflected, and then applying specific algorithms to the data set, it is possible to measure the amount of oxygenated hemoglobin and deoxygenated hemoglobin levels in any area of the brain. At first, the amount of oxygen is someone's brain seems almost trivial and useless. However, the amount of oxygen in someone's brain is directly proportional to their brain activity.
        There are many applications of this concept. For example, surgeons often perform complex procedures lasting many hours. Before the surgery, the surgeon will be at his peak and should be completely focused, however, as the surgery continues, the surgeon's focus will wear down. A tired surgeon will lead to surgical errors. However, if the surgeon wears the fNIR device and monitors oxygen levels throughout the surgery, there would eventually be a clear drop-off of oxygen concentration. When this oxygen level becomes very low, this is a sign that the initial surgeon is losing focus and a second surgeon could finish. This allows perfect management of resources for the hospital and could prevent many surgical errors. This is just one specific application, however, there are an infinite amount of applications waiting on this device.
        The reason the fNIR is so useful is because of its simplicity. While fMRIs produce a much better analysis of the brain, they are very complicated, expensive, and must be used by a medical professional. However, the goal of the fNIR is to create a brain analysis device available to the general public. A user of the fNIR simply buys a device, downloads the corresponding app, and clicks start. There is currently no device on the market allowing for such a simple way to analyze one's brain.
        Science and technology are constantly evolving. When the first computers were constructed, they were massive and complex. Only large companies and universities could afford and operate them. Now there are more computers than people. This is similar to the goal of the fNIR. In 2018, brain analysis can only be performed in hospitals and research centers and require knowledgeable professionals to operate. In the future, the fNIR could change this, allowing for anyone to measure brain performance at home, in the office, or on the road. The goal of our research is to make this dream a reality."
    </string>

    <string name="link_three"><a href="https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pmc/articles/PMC4033094/">3. What we can and cannot do with fNIR.</a></string>
    <string name="link_two"><a href="https://www.sciencedirect.com/science/article/pii/S1053811911006410?via%3Dihub">2. Brain monitoring for human operators using fNIR.</a></string>
    <string name="link_one"><a href="https://ieeexplore.ieee.org/stamp/stamp.jsp?arnumber=4272296">1. What is fNIR?</a></string>
    <string name="link_four"><a href="https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pmc/articles/PMC4309034/">4. Brain Computer Index Using fNIR.</a></string>


    <string-array name="filter_types">
        <item>None</item>
        <item>Simple FIR</item>
        <item>Butterworth IIR</item>
    </string-array>
    <string name="filter_help">
        "   These settings will adjust the filter for the data that is collected. By default, no filter is used. However, users have two options for filters: an FIR and an IIR.
        The FIR filter is a moving average filter. It simply averages a number of previous data samples with the current sample. The number of samples used in the averaging is determined by the filter order parameter, which is set to a defualt value of 5. This filter is very simple and quick, however, it is also very limited and does little besides smoothing the graph.
        The IIR filter is a butterworth filter. This is a type of low pass , which removes any frequencies above the frequency cutoff parameter. There are several different cutoff frequencies possible, and each have different uses. For most purposes, a cutoff frequency of .1 Hz will work as this frequency is slightly greater than the time it takes for any hemodynamic changes. Therefore a lot of noise will be removed without affecting the data.
        The IIR filter is a very powerful tool. For uses here, the default frequency does a good job of isolating the hemodynamic changes. However, this filter can also be used to determine heart rate or respiration rate by tweaking the parameters and adding a high pass filter. This application does not currently support this, but could easily be modified to do so.
    </string>
</resources>
